# **KUFORIJI, Fatimoh Yetunde**

#### **Contact**

+447574005766 | fatimohkuforiji@yahoo.com | LinkedIn Profile | GitHub Page

## Personal Statement

Cheerful and friendly person. As a passionate full stack developer, I have experience in producing software solutions from conception to deployment including creating database, graphic designing and working with several programming languages. I am interested in opportunities to make meaningful impacts and enhance my skills.

#### **Technical Skills**

Languages: CSS, HTML, React, JavaScript, Node, PostgreSQL, Express Platforms: GitHub, Heroku, Visual Studio Code, NPM RESTful API, Netlify

# Work Experience

#### Full Stack Web Developer Trainee

#### CodeYourFuture (CYF), Birmingham, UK (Sep 2020 - July 2021)

- Built several applications including a quiz application that enable engagement of teachers and students; high score tables for displaying and sorting scores of countries in ascending or descending order, and a baby name application for choosing and storing some common names of babies around the world.
- Enhanced my soft skills such as problem solving, communication skills, time management and critical thinking. I worked on personal project and practiced Agile methodologies for team work.

#### Carer and Home Manager

#### Birmingham, UK (Oct 2018 - Sep 2020)

- o Cared and managed a happy family of five
- Managed schedules and purchases, and created daily routines
- Enrolled and successfully completed an adult education course on mathematics
- Volunteered to teach basic Arabic language and Islamic studies to stay-at-home mums

#### Human Resource Manager

#### Athex Consulting Ltd, Lagos, Nigeria (Aug 2017 - Sep 2018)

- Established the HR department and developed people-oriented vision and strategies to support the company
- Managed staff recruitment and provided welfare support to employees
- Coordinated staff trainings and development

#### Company Secretary

#### Alege Enterprise, Lagos, Nigeria (2005)

- Receive and send correspondence on behalf of the firm
- o Register and communicate with company stakeholders
- Maintain proper financial record.

#### **Education**

#### University of Lagos, UNILAG

Master of Art (M.A.) in History and Strategic Studies

#### ■ Lagos State University, LASU

Bachelor of Art (B.A.) in History and International Studies

# Courses & Certifications

#### Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals

Microsoft Corporation

#### Diploma in Public Relations

Nigeria Institute of Public Relations (NIPR)

### Desktop Publishing

MAAF Computer College

### Awards

- Lagos State Government Post-graduate Scholarship, 2013/2014
- Overall Best Student (Diplomat Award), Department of History, LASU, 2010/2011
- Best Graduating Student in History and International Studies, LASU, 2009/2010

#### **Hobbies**

Travelling, sewing and spending time with my family